Mir Ehsanul Karim

Apt 604, Eastern Monzil, 8/5 Aurangzeb Road Mohammadpur, Dhaka 1207, Bangladesh

Cell Phone: +8801713078990 Email: karim.me@live.com



Background Summery

Senior Executive with diverse Management and International Apparels & fashion merchandising experience, from concept to execution with extensive experience in EU, US, Canada and Australian market. A strong leader with creativity & innovation skills with a proven track record of solid contributions to the strategic and financial success of organizations.

Professional Experience

Oct-2012 to present (Dhaka)
Fair Apparels Ltd.
Compliant composite knitwear manufacturer
Director, Marketing & operation

World of Textiles – Willy Maisel GmbH www.world-of-textiles.com Apparels (Knit, woven, sweater), Home textile, Towel, Cap, bags; have garment printing (direct & transfer) facility. Country Manager 2007 to Sep-12 (Dhaka)

N A Z Bangladesh Ltd. Compliant composite knitwear manufacturer GM, Marketing, Merchandising & operation 2004~2007 (Dhaka)

Waqfi Knitwear Ltd.
Compliant composite knitwear manufacturer
GM, Marketing & Merchandising
2001~2004 (Dhaka)

Jupiter RMG Ltd., Sharrat Knitwear Ltd.
Compliant manufacturer for woven bottom, knitwear
GM, Marketing & Merchandising
1999~2001(Dhaka)

Doel Group of Industries Garments (knit, Woven, Sweaters) manufacturer Manager, Merchandising - Garment Division 1996~1999 (Dhaka)

Chunji Industrial Co., Ltd., South Korea Manufacturer & Exporter for Sweater Yarn & Sweater Manager Sales and Merchandising 1993~1996 (Dhaka) Moller & Co., Denmark, Liaison office Buyer for apparels (Knit, Woven and Sweater) Sr. Executive, Merchandise & Commercial 1991~1993 (Dhaka)

Epic Designers HK Ltd.
Leading garment buying and Manufacturing Company
Jr Qc, Jr~Sr Merchandiser
1989~1991 (Chittagong)

Sunbeam Associates Agent of K-Line, Japan; Forwarder and consolidator Executive (Marketing / Documentation / Operation) 1985~1989 (Chittagong)

Skills

Management **Team Building** Leadership Marketing Merchandising **ERP** Planning Quality Assurance **Product Development** Sourcing **Price Negotiation** Raw Material quality & cost **Inventory Management** Apparel & Fashion Retail Supply Chain Management Factory matrix & capacity Compliance (ES & Tech) Risk Assessment Forecast Commercial Banking Shipping Logistic

Co-curricular skills

- Possess good Leadership, Coaching skills, passion to add value & eagerness to contribute, Problem solving
 and negotiation capability, Pro-active, Analytic & good reporting skill, Flexible & adaptable in adverse
 condition with a sense of ownership and belongingness.
- Garment Marketing & merchandizing, Raw material sourcing, quality, cost & procurement, Factory evaluation & management, Compliance issues, Manage factory matrix & capacity, Production process, Manage Fabric, trims, color accreditation & testing process, Quality assurance, merchandize inspection, Banking & Commercial, UCPDC, Master & Back to Back L/c, Customs, Bond, BGMEA, BKMEA, Export Promotion Bureau, Import & Export documentation, Proceeds realization, Liability adjustment, DEDO (duty Exemption and drawback), Cash Incentives, CNF, Shipping & Forwarding companies, Local and Foreign Investment in Garment sector, Registrar of Joint Stock Companies & Firms, Company affairs and taxation, Immigration & Passports, Board of Investment, Chamber of Commerce & Industry, BEPZA, etc.
- Extensive travel to attend buying meeting & production units, develop new customers, Pre-shipment &
 Post shipments problem solutions etc. from time to time.
- Experienced on customers from Europe, USA, Canada, Australia e.g. M&S, Tesco, Next, S Oliver, Sainsbury, Tom Tailor, Aldi, Lidl, Zara, Rewe, C&A, Gerry Weber, Kappa, Decathlon, Carrefour, Stadium, H&M, Adidas, Reebok, Sears, Walmart, Eddie Bauer, Komar, Amerella of Canada, Pac brand, Big W, etc..

Computer Skill

OS: Windows 98, Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8 environment

Office application: Word, Excel, Power Point, Outlook

Internet : Email, Browsing

Academic Qualification

Bachelor of Science City College, Chittagong - 1984 (2nd division)
Higher Secondary Certificate City College, Chittagong - 1982 (1st division)
Secondary School Certificate Model High School, Chittagong - 1979 (1st division)

Continued to page 3

Training Summery

Title	Topic	Institute	Location	Year / Duration
Apparel Design &	Commercial, Merchandising,	German	Dhaka,	1990 /
Merchandising	Production & Quality Control	Technical Center	Bangladesh	26 weeks

Linguistic Ability

Good communication skills (Read, Write, spoken) in English & Bengali

Interests

Garments, Global advancement, Movies, Music, Traveling, Photography.

Personal Details

Father's name : Mir Anwar Hossain (Late), Sr Superintendent of Police, Chittagong, Bangladesh

Mother's name : Saima Anwar

Permanent address : 299 Nazimuddin Road, Krishnapur 5/5, PO+PS+Dist: Pabna-6600, Bangladesh

Date of birth : July 20, 1963 at Pabna, Bangladesh

Nationality : Bangladeshi National ID no. : 2695046972770

Passport no. :

Driver's License no. : CG0031635L/1986

Religion : Islam
Sex : Male
Blood group : A+

Marital status : Married and blessed with 3 children; Son (24y), Daughter (21y), Son (5y)

Application Information

Present compensation : Tk

Available for : Full time Expected compensation : Tk

References

Available upon request.

Please revert if you need any further information and clarification.

Thanking you in anticipation.

Sincerely yours,

Mir Ehsanul Karim